[
    {
        "question": "The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases;(1) his mercies never come to an end; Footnotes (1) 3:22 Syriac, Targum; Hebrew *Because of the steadfast love of the Lord, we are not cut off* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:22",
        "rank": "1,398"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has made my flesh and my skin waste away; he has broken my bones; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:4",
        "rank": "2,000"
    },
    {
        "question": "How lonely sits the city that was full of people! How like a widow has she become, she who was great among the nations! She who was a princess among the provinces has become a slave. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:1",
        "rank": "3,215"
    },
    {
        "question": "he has besieged and enveloped me with bitterness and tribulation; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:5",
        "rank": "3,549"
    },
    {
        "question": "Judah has gone into exile because of affliction(1) and hard servitude; she dwells now among the nations, but finds no resting place; her pursuers have all overtaken her in the midst of her distress.(2) Footnotes (1) 1:3 Or *under affliction* (2) 1:3 Or *in the narrow passes* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:3",
        "rank": "3,585"
    },
    {
        "question": "Her foes have become the head; her enemies prosper, because the LORD has afflicted her for the multitude of her transgressions; her children have gone away, captives before the foe. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:5",
        "rank": "3,946"
    },
    {
        "question": "The roads to Zion mourn, for none come to the festival; all her gates are desolate; her priests groan; her virgins have been afflicted,(1) and she herself suffers bitterly. Footnotes (1) 1:4 Septuagint, Old Latin *dragged away* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:4",
        "rank": "3,955"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has cut down in fierce anger all the might of Israel; he has withdrawn from them his right hand in the face of the enemy; he has burned like a flaming fire in Jacob, consuming all around. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:3",
        "rank": "4,062"
    },
    {
        "question": "Those who once feasted on delicacies perish in the streets; those who were brought up in purple embrace ash heaps. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:5",
        "rank": "4,167"
    },
    {
        "question": "From the daughter of Zion all her majesty has departed. Her princes have become like deer that find no pasture; they fled without strength before the pursuer. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:6",
        "rank": "4,451"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jerusalem remembers in the days of her affliction and wandering all the precious things that were hers from days of old. When her people fell into the hand of the foe, and there was none to help her, her foes gloated over her; they mocked at her downfall. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:7",
        "rank": "4,816"
    },
    {
        "question": "he has made me dwell in darkness like the dead of long ago. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:6",
        "rank": "5,056"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jerusalem sinned grievously; therefore she became filthy; all who honored her despise her, for they have seen her nakedness; she herself groans and turns her face away. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:8",
        "rank": "5,074"
    },
    {
        "question": "The enemy has stretched out his hands over all her precious things; for she has seen the nations enter her sanctuary, those whom you forbade to enter your congregation. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:10",
        "rank": "5,092"
    },
    {
        "question": "All her people groan as they search for bread; they trade their treasures for food to revive their strength. \u201cLook, O LORD, and see, for I am despised.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:11",
        "rank": "5,212"
    },
    {
        "question": "Her uncleanness was in her skirts; she took no thought of her future;(1) therefore her fall is terrible; she has no comforter. \u201cO LORD, behold my affliction, for the enemy has triumphed!\u201d Footnotes (1) 1:9 Or *end* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:9",
        "rank": "5,277"
    },
    {
        "question": "For the chastisement(1) of the daughter of my people has been greater than the punishment(2) of Sodom, which was overthrown in a moment, and no hands were wrung for her.(3) Footnotes (1) 4:6 Or *iniquity* (2) 4:6 Or *sin* (3) 4:6 The meaning of the Hebrew is uncertain (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:6",
        "rank": "5,308"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cMy transgressions were bound(1) into a yoke; by his hand they were fastened together; they were set upon my neck; he caused my strength to fail; the Lord gave me into the hands of those whom I cannot withstand. Footnotes (1) 1:14 The meaning of the Hebrew is uncertain (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:14",
        "rank": "5,325"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cIs it nothing to you, all you who pass by? Look and see if there is any sorrow like my sorrow, which was brought upon me, which the LORD inflicted on the day of his fierce anger. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:12",
        "rank": "5,326"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cLet all their evildoing come before you, and deal with them as you have dealt with me because of all my transgressions; for my groans are many, and my heart is faint.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:22",
        "rank": "5,369"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cThe LORD is in the right, for I have rebelled against his word; but hear, all you peoples, and see my suffering; my young women and my young men have gone into captivity. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:18",
        "rank": "5,413"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has walled me about so that I cannot escape; he has made my chains heavy; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:7",
        "rank": "5,438"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cThe Lord rejected all my mighty men in my midst; he summoned an assembly against me to crush my young men; the Lord has trodden as in a winepress the virgin daughter of Judah. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:15",
        "rank": "5,480"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFrom on high he sent fire; into my bones(1) he made it descend; he spread a net for my feet; he turned me back; he has left me stunned, faint all the day long. Footnotes (1) 1:13 Septuagint; Hebrew *bones and* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:13",
        "rank": "5,498"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cFor these things I weep; my eyes flow with tears; for a comforter is far from me, one to revive my spirit; my children are desolate, for the enemy has prevailed.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:16",
        "rank": "5,577"
    },
    {
        "question": "Zion stretches out her hands, but there is none to comfort her; the LORD has commanded against Jacob that his neighbors should be his foes; Jerusalem has become a filthy thing among them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:17",
        "rank": "5,722"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cThey heard(1) my groaning, yet there is no one to comfort me. All my enemies have heard of my trouble; they are glad that you have done it. You have brought(2) the day you announced; now let them be as I am. Footnotes (1) 1:21 Septuagint, Syriac *Hear* (2) 1:21 Syriac *Bring* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:21",
        "rank": "5,794"
    },
    {
        "question": "he has blocked my ways with blocks of stones; he has made my paths crooked. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:9",
        "rank": "5,864"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has bent his bow like an enemy, with his right hand set like a foe; and he has killed all who were delightful in our eyes in the tent of the daughter of Zion; he has poured out his fury like fire. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:4",
        "rank": "6,042"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI called to my lovers, but they deceived me; my priests and elders perished in the city, while they sought food to revive their strength. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:19",
        "rank": "6,085"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cLook, O LORD, for I am in distress; my stomach churns; my heart is wrung within me, because I have been very rebellious. In the street the sword bereaves; in the house it is like death. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 1:20",
        "rank": "6,262"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now their face is blacker than soot; they are not recognized in the streets; their skin has shriveled on their bones; it has become as dry as wood. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:8",
        "rank": "6,325"
    },
    {
        "question": "though I call and cry for help, he shuts out my prayer; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:8",
        "rank": "6,518"
    },
    {
        "question": "We have given the hand to Egypt, and to Assyria, to get bread enough. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:6",
        "rank": "6,674"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord has become like an enemy; he has swallowed up Israel; he has swallowed up all its palaces; he has laid in ruins its strongholds, and he has multiplied in the daughter of Judah mourning and lamentation. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:5",
        "rank": "7,135"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has laid waste his booth like a garden, laid in ruins his meeting place; the LORD has made Zion forget festival and Sabbath, and in his fierce indignation has spurned king and priest. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:6",
        "rank": "7,308"
    },
    {
        "question": "he turned aside my steps and tore me to pieces; he has made me desolate; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:11",
        "rank": "7,650"
    },
    {
        "question": "He is a bear lying in wait for me, a lion in hiding; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:10",
        "rank": "7,676"
    },
    {
        "question": "Their princes were brighter than snow and whiter than milk, their bodies more ruddy than rubies, their appearance like lapis lazuli.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:7",
        "rank": "7,789"
    },
    {
        "question": "he bent his bow and set me as a target for his arrow. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:12",
        "rank": "7,878"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord has scorned his altar, disowned his sanctuary; he has delivered into the hand of the enemy the walls of her palaces; they raised a clamor in the house of the LORD as on the day of festival. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:7",
        "rank": "8,265"
    },
    {
        "question": "I am the man who has seen affliction under the rod of his wrath; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:1",
        "rank": "8,578"
    },
    {
        "question": "Remember my affliction and my wanderings, the wormwood and the gall! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:19",
        "rank": "8,752"
    },
    {
        "question": "Our fathers sinned, and are no more; and we bear their iniquities. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:7",
        "rank": "8,942"
    },
    {
        "question": "I have become the laughingstock of all peoples, the object of their taunts all day long. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:14",
        "rank": "8,977"
    },
    {
        "question": "The elders of the daughter of Zion sit on the ground in silence; they have thrown dust on their heads and put on sackcloth; the young women of Jerusalem have bowed their heads to the ground. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:10",
        "rank": "9,160"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD determined to lay in ruins the wall of the daughter of Zion; he stretched out the measuring line; he did not restrain his hand from destroying; he caused rampart and wall to lament; they languished together. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:8",
        "rank": "9,161"
    },
    {
        "question": "Her gates have sunk into the ground; their bars he has broken and destroyed. Her king and her princes are exiled among the nations, the law is no more, and her prophets no longer find visions from the LORD.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:9",
        "rank": "9,427"
    },
    {
        "question": "my soul is bereft of peace; I have forgotten what happiness(1) is; Footnotes (1) 3:17 Hebrew *good* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:17",
        "rank": "9,566"
    },
    {
        "question": "He drove into my kidneys the arrows of his quiver; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:13",
        "rank": "9,725"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD is good to those who wait for him, to the soul who seeks him. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:25",
        "rank": "9,769"
    },
    {
        "question": "they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:23",
        "rank": "9,972"
    },
    {
        "question": "All who pass along the way clap their hands at you; they hiss and wag their heads at the daughter of Jerusalem: \u201cIs this the city that was called the perfection of beauty, the joy of all the earth?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:15",
        "rank": "10,029"
    },
    {
        "question": "so I say, \u201cMy endurance has perished; so has my hope from the LORD.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:18",
        "rank": "10,091"
    },
    {
        "question": "They cry to their mothers, \u201cWhere is bread and wine?\u201d as they faint like a wounded man in the streets of the city, as their life is poured out on their mothers\u2019 bosom. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:12",
        "rank": "10,092"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has made my teeth grind on gravel, and made me cower in ashes; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:16",
        "rank": "10,213"
    },
    {
        "question": "Happier were the victims of the sword than the victims of hunger, who wasted away, pierced by lack of the fruits of the field. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:9",
        "rank": "10,268"
    },
    {
        "question": "All your enemies rail against you; they hiss, they gnash their teeth, they cry: \u201cWe have swallowed her! Ah, this is the day we longed for; now we have it; we see it!\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:16",
        "rank": "10,269"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cArise, cry out in the night, at the beginning of the night watches! Pour out your heart like water before the presence of the Lord! Lift your hands to him for the lives of your children, who faint for hunger at the head of every street.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:19",
        "rank": "10,450"
    },
    {
        "question": "My eyes are spent with weeping; my stomach churns; my bile is poured out to the ground because of the destruction of the daughter of my people, because infants and babies faint in the streets of the city. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:11",
        "rank": "10,707"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hands of compassionate women have boiled their own children; they became their food during the destruction of the daughter of my people. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:10",
        "rank": "10,787"
    },
    {
        "question": "My soul continually remembers it and is bowed down within me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:20",
        "rank": "10,788"
    },
    {
        "question": "Slaves rule over us, and there is none to free us from their hands.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:8",
        "rank": "10,868"
    },
    {
        "question": "He has filled me with bitter herbs and sated me with gall.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:15",
        "rank": "10,869"
    },
    {
        "question": "What can I say for you? With what can I compare you, Daughter Jerusalem? To what can I liken you, that I may comfort you, Virgin Daughter Zion? Your wound is as deep as the sea. Who can heal you?",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:13",
        "rank": "10,870"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is good to wait quietly for the salvation of the LORD.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:26",
        "rank": "11,213"
    },
    {
        "question": "How the Lord has covered Daughter Zion with the cloud of his anger! He has hurled down the splendor of Israel from heaven to earth; he has not remembered his footstool in the day of his anger.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:1",
        "rank": "11,282"
    },
    {
        "question": "The visions of your prophets were false and worthless; they did not expose your sin to ward off your captivity. The prophecies they gave you were false and misleading.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:14",
        "rank": "11,440"
    },
    {
        "question": "For people are not cast off by the Lord forever.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:31",
        "rank": "11,512"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD has given full vent to his wrath; he has poured out his fierce anger. He kindled a fire in Zion that consumed her foundations.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:11",
        "rank": "11,649"
    },
    {
        "question": "We get our bread at the risk of our lives because of the sword in the desert.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:9",
        "rank": "11,886"
    },
    {
        "question": "I say to myself, \"The LORD is my portion; therefore I will wait for him.\"",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:24",
        "rank": "11,887"
    },
    {
        "question": "The LORD has done what he planned; he has fulfilled his word, which he decreed long ago. He has overthrown you without pity, he has let the enemy gloat over you, he has exalted the horn of your foes.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:17",
        "rank": "12,039"
    },
    {
        "question": "Women have been ravished in Zion, and virgins in the towns of Judah.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:11",
        "rank": "12,122"
    },
    {
        "question": "he has driven and brought me into darkness without any light; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:2",
        "rank": "12,213"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Look, LORD, and consider: Whom have you ever treated like this? Should women eat their offspring, the children they have cared for? Should priest and prophet be killed in the sanctuary of the Lord?\"",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:20",
        "rank": "12,214"
    },
    {
        "question": "Our skin is hot as an oven with the burning heat of famine. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:10",
        "rank": "12,388"
    },
    {
        "question": "surely against me he turns his hand again and again the whole day long. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:3",
        "rank": "12,539"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the dust of the streets lie the young and the old; my young women and my young men have fallen by the sword; you have killed them in the day of your anger, slaughtering without pity. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:21",
        "rank": "12,540"
    },
    {
        "question": "let him give his cheek to the one who strikes, and let him be filled with insults. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:30",
        "rank": "12,703"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is good for a man that he bear the yoke in his youth. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:27",
        "rank": "12,704"
    },
    {
        "question": "The kings of the earth did not believe, nor any of the inhabitants of the world, that foe or enemy could enter the gates of Jerusalem. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:12",
        "rank": "12,783"
    },
    {
        "question": "Let him sit alone in silence when it is laid on him; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:28",
        "rank": "12,862"
    },
    {
        "question": "This was for the sins of her prophets and the iniquities of her priests, who shed in the midst of her the blood of the righteous. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:13",
        "rank": "13,006"
    },
    {
        "question": "You summoned as if to a festival day my terrors on every side, and on the day of the anger of the LORD no one escaped or survived; those whom I held and raised my enemy destroyed. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:22",
        "rank": "13,007"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Lord has swallowed up without mercy all the habitations of Jacob; in his wrath he has broken down the strongholds of the daughter of Judah; he has brought down to the ground in dishonor the kingdom and its rulers. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:2",
        "rank": "13,008"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rejoice and be glad, O daughter of Edom, you who dwell in the land of Uz; but to you also the cup shall pass; you shall become drunk and strip yourself bare. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:21",
        "rank": "13,082"
    },
    {
        "question": "The breath of our nostrils, the LORD\u2019s anointed, was captured in their pits, of whom we said, \u201cUnder his shadow we shall live among the nations.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:20",
        "rank": "13,083"
    },
    {
        "question": "Their heart cried to the Lord. O wall of the daughter of Zion, let tears stream down like a torrent day and night! Give yourself no rest, your eyes no respite! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 2:18",
        "rank": "13,163"
    },
    {
        "question": "How the gold has grown dim, how the pure gold is changed! The holy stones lie scattered at the head of every street. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:1",
        "rank": "13,473"
    },
    {
        "question": "Restore us to yourself, O LORD, that we may be restored! Renew our days as of old\u2014 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:21",
        "rank": "13,688"
    },
    {
        "question": "let him put his mouth in the dust\u2014 there may yet be hope; (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 3:29",
        "rank": "13,776"
    },
    {
        "question": "They wandered, blind, through the streets; they were so defiled with blood that no one was able to touch their garments. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:14",
        "rank": "13,991"
    },
    {
        "question": "The joy of our hearts has ceased; our dancing has been turned to mourning. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:15",
        "rank": "14,062"
    },
    {
        "question": "Young men are compelled to grind at the mill, and boys stagger under loads of wood. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:13",
        "rank": "14,140"
    },
    {
        "question": "Princes are hung up by their hands; no respect is shown to the elders. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 5:12",
        "rank": "14,141"
    },
    {
        "question": "The punishment of your iniquity, O daughter of Zion, is accomplished; he will keep you in exile no longer;(1) but your iniquity, O daughter of Edom, he will punish; he will uncover your sins. Footnotes (1) 4:22 Or *he will not exile you again* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:22",
        "rank": "14,142"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cAway! Unclean!\u201d people cried at them. \u201cAway! Away! Do not touch!\u201d So they became fugitives and wanderers; people said among the nations, \u201cThey shall stay with us no longer.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:15",
        "rank": "14,223"
    },
    {
        "question": "Because of thirst the infant's tongue sticks to the roof of its mouth; the children beg for bread, but no one gives it to them.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:4",
        "rank": "14,425"
    },
    {
        "question": "Moreover, our eyes failed, looking in vain for help; from our towers we watched for a nation that could not save us.",
        "answer": "Lamentations 4:17",
        "rank": "14,443"
    }
]